<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Charlotte Real Estate Video Blog with Scott Pridemore</title>
    <description>Our mission at Pridemore Properties is to be your best resource for Charlotte real estate advice. Whether you are a buyer, seller, or investor, our team of professionals can answer any questions you might have about real estate. If you are looking to buy or sell a home, you can get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Pridemore Properties, your professional Charlotte Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2021 14:08:08 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2021 14:08:08 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.7.4</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Are the Keys to Buying and Selling Homes in Our Market?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/hCyCncfCgGQ?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s how to successfully navigate our hot real estate market today.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of sellers have questions regarding how they might be able to sell their home while also positioning themselves to successfully buy another property. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this COVID climate, we start by taking all the standard precautions that the CDC has imposed. We also allow homebuyers and agents to view homes one at a time while using facemasks and hand sanitizer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=There is a huge opportunity for homebuyers to lock in a low interest rate.%20http://localhost:4000/what-are-the-keys-to-buying-and-selling-homes-in-our-market.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“There is a huge opportunity for homebuyers to lock in a low interest rate.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Homes aren’t taking long to sell at all. If you’re worried about selling too quickly and not being able to find a new home in time, we can help with that. &lt;strong&gt;We can connect buyers and sellers, align the times just right, and even lease the sold home back from the buyer for up to 60 days to find that new property if necessary.&lt;/strong&gt; This gives our sellers a bit of a buffer and eases some of the stress that comes with buying in a low inventory market like this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s not just about finding properties on the MLS if you’re a buyer. With record low inventory, you need to get creative. Good agents will be able to find properties that aren’t even listed. Sellers are earning top dollar right now, and most listings on the MLS are getting multiple offers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the same time, there’s also a huge opportunity for homebuyers to lock in a low interest rate. &lt;strong&gt;Statistics indicate that we’re headed into further reduced inventory based on current demand.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about buying a home, selling a home, or real estate in general, don’t hesitate to reach out via phone or email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/what-are-the-keys-to-buying-and-selling-homes-in-our-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/what-are-the-keys-to-buying-and-selling-homes-in-our-market.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Buyers Should Know About New Construction</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/XX7EBMkcMIo?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s what buyers need to know about new construction homes.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As far as new construction goes, there is a litany of options in our marketplace, ranging across many price points and types of builds. What many don’t realize, though, is that a lot of these homes aren’t even in the MLS. Many times, a for-sale sign in the front yard will attract buyers to a new property before the first brick has even been laid. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;But what are the benefits of buying new construction? Here are just a few:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.&lt;/strong&gt; Everything is brand-new. You’ll be the first one to ever live in the home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.&lt;/strong&gt; You can often customize the home, including paint colors and hardware.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3.&lt;/strong&gt; Everything is under warranty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=You’ll need a buyer’s agent to help you navigate the nuances of the builder’s contract.%20http://localhost:4000/what-buyers-should-know-about-new-construction.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“You’ll need a buyer’s agent to help you navigate the nuances of the builder’s contract.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re thinking of buying a new construction home, we &lt;strong&gt;highly recommend that you order a home inspection.&lt;/strong&gt; Yes, the home is brand-new, but we’ve seen inspection reports come back with upwards of 50 items that need to be addressed prior to closing. It’s also critical to hire a buyer’s agent. Most builders will use contracts that contain inclusions and exclusions, and it’s our job as agents to make sure that the builder completes per the finish standards in the contract and that you, as a buyer, are cognizant of what you’re signing. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We help buyers purchase new construction homes throughout Charlotte all the time, so if you have any questions or need any assistance, don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We’d love to help you, as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2021 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/what-buyers-should-know-about-new-construction.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/what-buyers-should-know-about-new-construction.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What’s Going on in the Charlotte Real Estate Market</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/AFcJV3B-ltk?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mike Hege joins me to discuss the facts and dispel unhelpful hysteria surrounding the performance of our real estate market amid the COVID-19 pandemic.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite what you may be hearing, real estate is still moving. As my guest, Mike Hege, explains, there are fundamental principles associated with prudent home selling and home buying that don’t change when the circumstances do. Of course, there are fewer listings these days, but at its core, our real estate market is still healthy—and it’s primed to stay healthy. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cited below for your convenience are timestamps that will direct you to various points in the video. Feel free to watch it in its entirety or use these timestamps to browse specific points at your leisure: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1:37 - How and why smart, financially prudent buyers are still buying in this environment&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4:41 - Don’t make your long-term decisions based on short-term problems&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7:57 - Addressing the misleading notion that home values are decreasing &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8:44 - Pent-up buyer demand could fuel a V-shaped recovery &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10:16 - The two types of buyers and sellers in our market right now &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;13:37 - Contrasting the current crisis with the Great Recession of 2008 &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;16:26 - How lending practices have changed since the Great Recession &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;18:39 - Ideas on how to help local businesses amid the pandemic &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;22:18 - TreesCharlotte’s awesome Earth Day promotion: Free tree seedlings &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;23:48 - Wrapping things up &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope you found this discussion both informative and positive. If you have further questions about what was touched on in this video, or if you’re interested in buying or selling a home soon but aren’t sure how to proceed in these times, reach out to us. We’re always here to help.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 13:16:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/whats-going-on-in-the-charlotte-real-estate-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/whats-going-on-in-the-charlotte-real-estate-market.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>We’re Dedicated to Keeping Our Clients Safe and Healthy</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/C05pMr1y_a8?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;Although the coronavirus pandemic has interrupted and significantly changed our daily lives, we&amp;rsquo;re still doing our best to adapt to the situation and ensure our clients are safe and healthy.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope you and your family are doing well and healthy. As our daily lives change during the coronavirus outbreak and subsequent shutdown, I want you to know how our team is adapting to keep servicing our clients while also keeping them safe and healthy. Given our Mecklenburg County order to stay at home, we’re doing a lot more things digitally these days. I look forward to sharing some of these exciting new things that we’re doing to help our clients in the wake of this global pandemic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2020 05:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/were-dedicated-to-keeping-our-clients-safe-and-healthy.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/were-dedicated-to-keeping-our-clients-safe-and-healthy.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Position Yourself to Come Out on Top in a Multiple-Offer Situation</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/cKkDmkkc360?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;As a buyer in our Charlotte market, here&amp;rsquo;s how you can come out on top if you find yourself in a multiple-offer situation.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If a listed home is priced well, move-in ready, and in a good location, more than one buyer will see the value in it, hence multiple-offer situations. We’re in a seller’s market here in Charlotte and our economy is strong, which means &lt;strong&gt;we’re seeing many bidding wars break out over available homes&lt;/strong&gt;. As a buyer, how can you position yourself in the best way possible so that you win out in a multiple-offer situation and close on the home you want? Mike Hege joins me today to answer that question by offering some valuable tips. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember, if you have questions about this or any real estate topic, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’m here to help.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2020 10:52:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/position-yourself-to-come-out-on-top-in-a-multiple-offer-situation.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/position-yourself-to-come-out-on-top-in-a-multiple-offer-situation.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Can You Trust a Zestimate?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/dDgHuqRVkO0?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ve probably heard of Zillow&amp;rsquo;s Zestimates&amp;mdash;automated home value estimates&amp;mdash;but how much do you really know about them? Here&amp;rsquo;s what you need to know about Zestimates.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of Zillow’s most attractive features is its Zestimate, which is an automated home valuation. This estimate is generated based on user-submitted data regarding the house in question as well as information derived from public records. To many people, this seems like a quick and easy way to figure out how much a property is worth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many may not realize that homeowners and their agents can go to the site and suggest that certain changes have been made to a property in order to alter their Zestimate. So how trustworthy are Zestimates? &lt;strong&gt;Today, Mike Hege joins me to discuss what homebuyers and sellers need to understand when it comes to Zestimates.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feel free to follow our discussion in the video above or use the timestamps below to navigate the video at your leisure:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1:25—How Zestimates are calculated and how they can be altered&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2:45—Why, as people make changes to their homes, Zestimates become less relevant&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5:00—Zestimates as a baseline&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5:43—The appraisal process&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7:41—How Zestimates ultimately fall short of true market value&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;9:04—Work with a real estate professional to help you avoid misinformation&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about Zestimates or would like an accurate home valuation, don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We’d be happy to help you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2020 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/can-you-trust-a-zestimate.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/can-you-trust-a-zestimate.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How We Maximize Value For Our Seller Clients</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/7c6J3GeLXZQ?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In an excerpt from our latest podcast, we discussed how agents can maximize the home value of their sellers. Mike Hege and I roleplayed a few situations, gave some recommendations, and discussed the topic in depth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here’s an outline of our discussion, with timestamps so that you can skip ahead to the section(s) that interest you most:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;0:40- The very first thing we do with every home seller&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1:35- Why it’s important to ask a lot of questions&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3:05- How you can bring a ton of value through negotiating expertise&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4:20- How long does it take to properly prepare a home for the market?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6:10- Why timing is so important when launching a property&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8:30- The retail component of homebuyer logic&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10:35- How statistics play a role in helping sellers set their price and achieve their goals&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;12:30- Wrapping things up&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for me, don’t hesitate to reach out via phone or email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2020 13:47:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-we-maximize-value-for-our-seller-clients.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/how-we-maximize-value-for-our-seller-clients.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How We Provide Value to Today’s Homebuyers</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/5s5D3grOnVc?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it comes to bringing extra value to today’s homebuyers, Realtor Mike Hege emphasizes the importance of giving honest feedback. &lt;strong&gt;Agents shouldn’t pull any punches&lt;/strong&gt;; if the property the buyer is interested in needs major repairs, they should help their client understand why they shouldn’t buy the house. As a fiduciary and consultant to their clients, agents need to be upfront. At Pridemore Properties, Mike holds a buyer consultation where he walks the buyer through the process, shows them properties, and even shares the listing agent’s remarks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A good agent also needs to help buyers understand that a home purchase is a process of elimination, not a process of selection. There is a difference between a buyer’s must-haves and their wants, and &lt;strong&gt;our goal is to keep their options in a sort of funnel that begins with a wide array of options and eventually narrows down&lt;/strong&gt; to specific areas, homes, and property features/amenities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=A home purchase is a process of elimination, not a process of selection.%20http://localhost:4000/how-we-provide-value-to-todays-homebuyers.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“A home purchase is a process of elimination, not a process of selection.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, it’s important to remember that &lt;strong&gt;buyers all want different things in a home&lt;/strong&gt;. Some want a house near the airport or interstate, others want a home with recreational outlets nearby, and some want to be closer to their family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, consider the fact that &lt;strong&gt;interest rates are currently at an all-time low.&lt;/strong&gt; This means it might be a good idea for a hesitant buyer to jump into the market; home affordability increases when interest rates are low.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re considering a move in 2020, now is a good time to start having that conversation with a professional. Let’s familiarize you with the home buying process, the competition, the available inventory—the more information you have now, the more you’ll be armed with when the right property for you comes on the market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t hesitate to reach out to us for help or any questions you have. We’d be glad to help you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2020 16:35:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-we-provide-value-to-todays-homebuyers.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/how-we-provide-value-to-todays-homebuyers.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Agents Maximize Value for Their Clients</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/2QeDAZJl-NU?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The art of maximizing value is a broad topic in the real estate industry. It can refer to the value we agents bring to the marketplace, how we help maximize the value of sellers’ homes, the perceived value of investments for buyers, and so on. Today I’m joined by fellow agent Mike Hege to talk about how agents maximize value for their clients. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Follow along in the video above to see our full discussion. For your convenience, I’ve provided timestamps so you can skip ahead to various sections: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;0:54—Bringing value in terms of who you hire to help you buy or sell&lt;br /&gt;1:41—The value of referrals &lt;br /&gt;2:27—The common denominator for any successful real estate agent&lt;br /&gt;3:19—There’s more at stake for agents than just the transaction&lt;br /&gt;4:27—What makes the difference between a loyal customer and a raving fan&lt;br /&gt;5:12—Why reputation is more important than a billboard &lt;br /&gt;6:55—Wrapping things up &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for me about this topic, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d love to help you. &lt;br /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2019 14:37:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-agents-maximize-value-for-their-clients.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/how-agents-maximize-value-for-their-clients.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Welcome To My Blog</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Our market remains busy, and it’s still an opportune time to command a high price selling your home.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I know what’s happening in the Charlotte Metro area, specifically pertaining to home values, that will directly affect you.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I’ll be posting two monthly video messages on this blog to keep you updated. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They will be valuable and useful in helping you stay on top of what’s happening in the community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check back because content will be coming soon!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m excited to keep you updated on what’s happening in the Charlotte Metro area!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2019 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/welcome-to-my-blog.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/welcome-to-my-blog.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
